Dale Chang Software Engineer

San Diego, CA (willing to relocate or work remote) (720) 419-9441 dalecb13@gmail.com

Technology Stack

Front-end

- Angular 8+, RxJS, Material, Jasmine, VS Code
- Sketch, Adobe XD

Middleware

- Python 3 Flask, Falcon
- Java Spring REST

Data Layer

- SQL MySQL, PostgreSQL
- NoSQL HBase, HDFS, MongoDB
- Document Lucene Solr 5-7, Elasticsearch 6

Analytics

- Deep Learning
- Supervised & Unsupervised Machine Learning
- AWS SageMaker + Jupyter Notebook
- SparkML 1.6 & 2.1+

Streaming/Messaging

- Kafka
- Apache NiFi

Infrastructure

- Linux
- Docker
- OpenShift-managed Kubernetes
- Jenkins CI/CD
- Mac OSX

SDLC

- Agile + Scrum
- Git
- Atlassian suite (JIRA, Confluence)
- Rally

Summary & Objective

I am a senior full-stack software engineer with 6+ years of experience across the enterprise computing stack, including front-end, middleware, back-end, DevOps, and analytics experience in AWS. In my next role, I am interested in solidifying my overall software development experience and then transition into an overall Solutions Architect role in the next few years.

Experience

Cigna - Software Engineering Senior Advisor

Feb 2019 - present @ Remote in San Diego, CA

Client Management Platform (CMP) is a financial application which shows diagnostics, summaries, and trends on how client customers' employees are using healthcare

- Lead design and development of features from end-to-end, from developing dashboards in Angular 8+ to NodeJS + Python REST APIs in AWS Lambda and API Gateway
- Wireframed and developed reusable components in Sketch and Adobe XD through meetings with stakeholders
- Lead knowledge transfer sessions for Angular development to junior members of the team
- Developed Jenkins CI/CD pipelines for continuous integration and automated deployments
- Provisioned production resources in AWS using Hashicorp Terraform

Leidos (CAADS) - Data Integration Engineer

April 2018 - Jan 2019 @ Gaithersburg, MD

Collaborative Advanced Analytics & Data Sharing (CAADS) is a data lake and self-service + guided platform targeted to help federal health-focused agencies identify trends in their data.

- Lead the development of NLP ingestion and analytics pipelines via Apache Spark 2+, Apache Tika, and Solr on Cloudera Hadoop
- Developed, refined, and automated training & evaluation of machine learning inference models
- Developed REST APIs for querying, updating, and saving data in
- Defined requirements and developed/demoed prototypes and dashboards to clients
- Developed and tuned LSTM and bidirectional autoencoder neural network models for supervised machine learning inference on electronic documents

Leidos (Department of Justice) - Text Analytics and Software Analyst

Feb 2016 - March 2018 @ Washington DC

Collaborative Open Base for Review and Analytics (COBRA) is a big data, on premise open source platform for legal review and e-discovery. Federal agencies with non-existent litigation budgets use the platform to upload, organize, and identify documents with pertinent evidence for court matters.

- Developed ETL pipelines for batch uploads of electronic documents and images via OCR with Apache Tika
- Architected and lead development of an automated continuous active learning pipeline for gradually improving supervised machine learning models for document classification
- Fine-tuned and vetted results document classifier results with machine learning SMEs
- Lead analytics team members in developing a system-wide audit system for capturing deltas in state

Certifications & Clearances

- AWS Certified Developer Associate, valid from June 2021 to June 2024
- Public Trust Security Clearance with the Federal Department of Justice
 - o Active until 2022
- Public Trust Security Clearance with the Federal Human & Health Services
 - Active until 2023

Education History

University of Virginia - Bachelor's in Physics

Graduated Spring 2013 @ Charlottesville, VA

- As a TA, lead weekly mentoring sessions on software and robotics design
- As a materials researcher, analyzed efficiency and identified flaws in commercial solar panels with scanning probe microscopy and electron microscopy
- As an applied physics data analyst, evaluated sub-atomic particle collision data from the LHC accelerator in CERN
 using Linux and C++ to corroborate the discovery of the Higgs boson

Side Projects

Eloquia - Founder

Sept 2020 - Present @ Remote

Eloquia is a start-up dedicated to solving problems using technology in a variety of different spaces.

- Designed and developed dashboards for analyzing project and personnel productivity
- Gather requirements, propose suggestions, and demonstrate improvement to clients

Hobbies/Interests

- Rock climbing, bouldering, hiking, gravel biking
- Reading software development articles on Medium
- Developing platforms and apps to solve problems and improve quality of life